A Guide to the Trilateral Commission (North America) records FA420
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Office Files, 1972-1996; 1972-1983; 6; 19.16 Cubic Feet 47 letter document boxes and 1 record storage box
  - Press Clippings, 6.4
    - Publications - Japanese, 1974-1977 (Box 357, Folder 3577)
    - Printers (Box 357, Folder 3578)
    - Spett Printing, 1976-1977 (Box 357, Folder 3579)
    - Integraphic Technology (IT) (Chet Humbert) (Box 357, Folder 3580)
    - Middle East Trialogue Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 357, Folder 3581)
    - Trialogue 22, 1980 (Box 357, Folder 3582)
    - Trialogue Advisory Board, 1981-1984 (Box 357, Folder 3583)
    - Trialogue, 1981 September (Box 357, Folder 3584)
- Financial records, 1972-1997; 7; 7.6 Cubic Feet 20 letter document boxes
  Much of the Commission's day-to-day financial material was discarded prior to shipment of the archival records to the Rockefeller Archive Center, and is therefore not contained in the archives of the Trilateral Commission (North America). Financial records documenting activities of the past five years are maintained in the Washington D.C. office.
  In the Commission's first triennium (July 1973-June 1976) all program expenses were covered out of the North American office in New York. In the second triennium, a system was put in place - termed the "balancing of accounts" - for program expenses to be shared among the three areas and for a coordination contribution to be made by Europe and Japan to North America. Archival holdings are available documenting the balancing of accounts, 1976-1988.
  Funding for Commission operations was obtained from corporations and private foundations. Early funding sources documented in the archival collection include, but are not limited to: David Rockefeller, the Kettering Foundation, the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, the Lilly Endowment and the Ford Foundation.
  The collection also contains a selection of financial statements and reports for the period 1973-1997.
  - Trilateral Commission N.A. Financial Statements, 1984 (Box 358, Folder 3585)
  - Official Financial Statements, 1975-1976 through 1978-1979, 1975-1979 (Box 358, Folder 3586)
  - Official Financial Statements, 1979-1980 through 1981-1982, 1979-1982 (Box 358, Folder 3587)
  - Official Financial Statements, 1982-1983 through 1985-1986, 1982-1986 (Box 358, Folder 3588)
  - Audited Financial Statements, 1985-1986 through 1990-1991, 1985-1991 (Box 358, Folder 3589)
  - Audited Financial Statements, 1991-1992 through 1996-1997, 1991-1997 (Box 358, Folder 3590)
  - Real Estate Tax Issue, 1973-1995 (Box 359, Folder 3591)
  - Approval of Omega Purchase, 1982 (Box 359, Folder 3592)
  - Corporate, 1973-1990 (Box 359, Folder 3593)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1972-1973 (Box 359, Folder 3594)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1974 (Box 359, Folder 3595)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1975 (Box 359, Folder 3596)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1976 (Box 359, Folder 3597)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1977 (Box 359, Folder 3598)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1978 (Box 359, Folder 3599)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1979 (Box 359, Folder 3600)
  - Correspondence with Lawyers, etc., 1980-1995 (Box 359, Folder 3601)
  - Executive Committee Consents to the use of Letterhead (Box 360, Folder 3602)
  - Finance - Fundraising
  - Fundraising - Correspondence, 1987-1999 (Box 360, Folder 3603)
  - Contribution History, 1974-2001 (Box 360, Folder 3604)
  - Memos to David Rockefeller, Kennan, Victor, 1989-1997 (Box 360, Folder 3605)
  - Cover Memos to Paul Volcker, 1998-2001 (Box 360, Folder 3606)
  - Rockefeller, 1992-1995 (Box 360, Folder 3607)
  - Went, 1994-1995 (Box 360, Folder 3608)
  - Labrecque, 1994 (Box 360, Folder 3609)
  - Haas, 1994-1995 (Box 360, Folder 3610)
  - Fundraising - Correspondence, 1985-1994 (Box 360, Folder 3611)
  - Trilateral Development Committee, 1994 (Box 360, Folder 3611A)
  - Corporate Solicitation for Funds for Third Triennium, 1979-1980 (Box 360, Folder 3612)
  - Foundation Matters, 1977-1978 (Box 360, Folder 3613)
  - Foundation Grants, 1976-1979 (Box 360, Folder 3614)
  - Donner Foundation Grant and Accounting, 1977-1978 (Box 360, Folder 3615)
  - Ford Foundation Grants, 1977-1979 (Box 361, Folder 3616)
  - Ford Foundation, 1979-1980 (Box 361, Folder 3617)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1979-1990 (Box 361, Folder 3618)
  - Michel David-Weill, 1983-1991 (Box 361, Folder 3619)
  - Edmund D. Rothschild Foundation, 1979-1989 (Box 361, Folder 3620)
  - United States-Japan Fdn, 1991-1992 (Box 361, Folder 3621)
  - Emily & Ernest Woodruff Fund, 1980 (Box 361, Folder 3622)
  - Gund Foundation, 1979 (Box 361, Folder 3623)
  - William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, 1985-1992 (Box 361, Folder 3624)
  - German Marshall Fund, 1979-1992 (Box 361, Folder 3625)
  - W. Alton Jones Foundation, Inc., 1983 (Box 361, Folder 3626)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1980 (Box 361, Folder 3627)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1979-1988 (Box 361, Folder 3628)
  - John D. and Catherine T. Macarthur Foundation, 1979-1990 (Box 361, Folder 3629)
  - McDonnell Foundation (Box 361, Folder 3630)
  - Packard Foundation, 1988-1991 (Box 361, Folder 3630A)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1979 (Box 361, Folder 3631)
  - Toyota Fund - Submission, 1978 July (Box 361, Folder 3632)
  - Woodruff Fund, Inc., 1980 (Box 361, Folder 3633)
  - George Gund Foundation - Submission, 1979 May 10 (Box 361, Folder 3634)
  - The George Gund Foundation (Box 362, Folder 3635)
  - Hearst Foundation, 1979 (Box 362, Folder 3635A)
  - William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, 1982-1985 (Box 362, Folder 3636)
  - Johnson Foundation, 1977-1978 (Box 362, Folder 3637)
  - Charles P. Kettering Foundation, 1976-1982 (Box 362, Folder 3638)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1973-1985 (Box 362, Folder 3639)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1973-1985 (Box 362, Folder 3640)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1976-1982 (Box 362, Folder 3641)
  - Edmund De Rothschild Foundation, 1977-1983 (Box 363, Folder 3642)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Box 363, Folder 3643)
  - Memo/DB Overview, 1978 (Box 363, Folder 3644)
  - Henry Luce Foundation (Box 363, Folder 3644A)
  - Ford Foundation - Second Triennium Grant, 1976-1979 (Box 363, Folder 3645)
  - Ford Foundation - Third Triennium Grant, 1979-1982 (Box 363, Folder 3646)
  - Fleischmann Foundation, 1979 (Box 363, Folder 3647)
  - German Marshall Fund, 1977-1981 (Box 363, Folder 3648)
  - German Marshall Fund - Employment, etc. - Task Force Submission, 1979 August 29 (Box 363, Folder 3649)
  - McKnight Foundation, 1978-1980 (Box 363, Folder 3650)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation - Submission, 1979 May 14 (Box 363, Folder 3651)
  - George S. Franklin - Foundation Papers, 1974-1978 (Box 363, Folder 3652)
  - European Cultural Foundation, 1973 (Box 364, Folder 3653)
  - The Donner Foundation, 1975-1982 (Box 364, Folder 3654)
  - Annenberg Fund, 1983-1992 (Box 364, Folder 3655)
  - Florence V. Burden Foundation, 1979 (Box 364, Folder 3656)
  - Donner Foundation, 1983 (Box 364, Folder 3657)
  - The Japan Foundation - Center for Global Partnership, 1992-1993 (Box 364, Folder 3658)
  - The Japan Foundation - Center for Global Partnership, 1991-1993 (Box 364, Folder 3659)
  - Grants, 1976-1982 (Box 365, Folder 3660)
  - Foundation Support (Box 365, Folder 3661)
  - Atlantic Institute, 1974-1979 (Box 365, Folder 3662)
  - Charles E. Merrill Foundation (Box 365, Folder 3663)
  - Corporations - Lists with GSF Markings of Earnings from S&P Stock Guide (Box 365, Folder 3664)
  - Foundations, 1991 (Box 365, Folder 3665)
  - Financial Picture for Triennium (ending June 30, 1985), 1982-1985 (Box 365, Folder 3666)
  - Past Supporters, 1987-1991 (Box 365, Folder 3666A)
  - Cold Solicitations, 1991 (Box 365, Folder 3667)
  - Contributors, 1979-1988 (Box 366, Folder 3668)
  - Contributors, 1984-1985 (Box 366, Folder 3669)
  - Corporations giving Int'l Orgs. - Responses to Trilateral Mailing, 1984 (Box 366, Folder 3670)
  - Master TC Program (Box 366, Folder 3671)
  - Solicitation of June 1983 - Follow Up Letters, 1983 October 28 (Box 366, Folder 3672)
  - Follow Up Fundraising, 1982 (Box 366, Folder 3673)
  - Solicitations, 1984 (Box 366, Folder 3674)
  - Solicitations, 1982 (Box 366, Folder 3675)
  - Solicitations, 1982 (Box 366, Folder 3676)
  - Recipients 1982-1985, 1984 November 21 (Box 366, Folder 3677)
  - Original Recap Sheets, 1983 June 30 (Box 366, Folder 3678)
  - Abbott Labs (Box 366, Folder 3679)
  - Dunn and Bradstreet Corp. (Box 366, Folder 3680)
  - Citibank, N.A., 1982-1985 (Box 366, Folder 3681)
  - Solicitations, 1983-1992 (Box 366, Folder 3681A)
  - Diamond Shamrock, Inc. (Box 366, Folder 3682)
  - Solicitations, 1984-1985 (Box 366, Folder 3683)
  - Hearst Newspaper (The Hearst Foundation) (Box 367, Folder 3684)
  - Solicitations, 1982-1991 (Box 367, Folder 3685A)
  - Solicitations, 1979-1992 (Box 367, Folder 3685)
  - McDonnell-Douglas, 1983 (Box 367, Folder 3686)
  - Solicitations, 1983-1991 (Box 367, Folder 3687)
  - Pilsbury, 1982-1984 (Box 367, Folder 3688)
  - The Parsons Corporation, 1984-1988 (Box 367, Folder 3689)
  - PPG Industries (Box 367, Folder 3690)
  - Rexnord, 1986 (Box 367, Folder 3691)
  - Parsons and Whitmore, 1983-1991 (Box 367, Folder 3692)
  - Solicitations, 1984-1992 (Box 367, Folder 3693)
  - Fundraising - Individual Records, 1974-1983 (Box 367, Folder 3694)
  - Individual Solicitations, 1978-1982 (Box 367, Folder 3695)
  - TC Members Responses to DR Request for Help with Corporate Giving (Box 368, Folder 3696)
  - TC Members Responses to DR Request for Help with Corporate Giving (Box 368, Folder 3696A)
  - TC Members Responses to DR Request for Help with Corporate Giving (Box 368, Folder 3696B)
  - Corporations to be Solicited by Commissioners (Box 368, Folder 3697)
  - Corporations to be Solicited by Commissioners (Box 368, Folder 3698)
  - Fundraising, 1983-1984 (Box 368, Folder 3699)
  - Ford Foundation, 1973-1976 (Box 369, Folder 3700)
  - Sumitomo Fund, 1978 (Box 369, Folder 3701)
  - German Marshall Fund, 1973-1979 (Box 369, Folder 3702)
  - Toyota Submission, 1978 (Box 369, Folder 3703)
  - Kettering Foundation, 1973 (Box 369, Folder 3704)
  - Kettering - LDCs, 1973-1976 (Box 370, Folder 3705)
  - Volkswagen, 1977-1978 (Box 370, Folder 3706)
  - Volkswagen (Box 370, Folder 3707)
  - Stiftung Volkswagenwerk - Submission to Volkswagen Foundation, 1976 (Box 370, Folder 3708)
  - Volkswagen - Closing Report; Correspondence (Box 370, Folder 3709)
  - Japanese Contribution to Program, 1975 (Box 370, Folder 3710)
  - European Expenses, 1973-1977 (Box 370, Folder 3711)
  - Japanese Expenses (Box 371, Folder 3712)
  - Foundations, 1972-1973 (Box 371, Folder 3713)
  - Ford Grant Bank Account Food Meeting (Box 371, Folder 3714)
  - Ford Appeal (Box 371, Folder 3714A)
  - Ford Food Meeting Grant (Box 371, Folder 3714B)
  - Ford Grant (Box 371, Folder 3714C)
  - Complete Scaife Letter, 1978 November 17 (Box 371, Folder 3715)
  - Financial Support - Corporate (Box 371, Folder 3716)
  - Fundraising by David Rockefeller, 1982-1983 (Box 372, Folder 3717)
  - TC Summary for Foundations (Box 372, Folder 3718)
  - Finance Memos and Fundraising (Box 372, Folder 3719)
  - New Listings of Corporations (Publication Mailings), 1983 (Box 372, Folder 3720)
  - Possible Corporate Patrons - Dinner with Stockman, 1981-1982 (Box 372, Folder 3721)
  - Financial Status, 1980; 1983 (Box 372, Folder 3721A)
  - Balancing of Accounts with Europe and Japan
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1976-1977 (Box 372, Folder 3722)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1976-1977 (Box 372, Folder 3723)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1976-1977; 1977-1978 (Box 372, Folder 3724)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1977-1978 (Box 373, Folder 3725)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1979 (Box 373, Folder 3726)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1978-1979 (Box 373, Folder 3727)
    - Account Balance Administration, 1979 (Box 373, Folder 3727A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1979-1980 (Box 373, Folder 3728)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1979-1980 (Box 373, Folder 3729)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1979-1980 (Box 373, Folder 3729A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1979-1980 (Box 373, Folder 3729B)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1979-1980 (Box 373, Folder 3729C)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1980-1981 (Box 373, Folder 3730)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1981-1982 (Box 374, Folder 3731)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1981-1982 (Box 374, Folder 3731A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1981-1982 (Box 374, Folder 3731B)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1981-1982 (Box 374, Folder 3731C)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1981-1982 (Box 374, Folder 3731)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1982-1983 (Box 374, Folder 3732)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1982-1983 (Box 374, Folder 3732A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1982-1983 (Box 374, Folder 3732B)
    - Balancing of Accounts - Expenses and Receipts Estimates, 1983 June (Box 374, Folder 3733)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1983-1984 (Box 374, Folder 3734)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1983-1984 (Box 374, Folder 3734A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1983-1984 (Box 374, Folder 3734B)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1983-1984 (Box 374, Folder 3734C)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1984-1985 (Box 374, Folder 3735)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1984-1985 (Box 374, Folder 3736)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1985-1986 (Box 375, Folder 3737)
    - Old Projects, 1990-1991 (Box 375, Folder 3738)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1987-1988 (Box 375, Folder 3739)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1987-1988 (Box 375, Folder 3739A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1987-1988 (Box 375, Folder 3739B)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1987-1988 (Box 375, Folder 3739C)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1986-1987 (Box 375, Folder 3740)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1986-1987 (Box 375, Folder 3740A)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1986-1987 (Box 375, Folder 3740B)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1986-1987; 1987-1988 (Box 375, Folder 3741)
    - Balancing of Accounts, 1985-1986 (Box 375, Folder 3742)
  - Bond Beebe (Accountants) - Correspondence (Box 376, Folder 3743)
  - Bond Beebe (Accountants) - Financial Statements, 1973-1977 (Box 376, Folder 3744)
  - Bond Beebe (Accountants) - Financial Statements, 1973-1977 (Box 376, Folder 3744A)
  - Bond Beebe (Accountants) - Financial Statements, 1973-1977 (Box 376, Folder 3744B)
  - Matters re: Fundraising, 1977-1980 (Box 376, Folder 3745)
  - Foundation Fundraising, 1977-1980 (Box 376, Folder 3745A)
  - Fundraising Dinner, 1983 (Box 376, Folder 3745B)
  - Fundraising Dinner, 1984 (Box 376, Folder 3746)
  - North American Budget, 1982-1985 Triennium (Box 376, Folder 3747)
  - Work Lists for Corporate Solicitations - First Drafts, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3748)
  - Fundraising Lists, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3749)
  - Corporate Patron Letter, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3750)
  - Master Copy of Corporation Letter (Box 377, Folder 3751)
  - Ambassador Mansfield Dinner (for Corporate Patrons), 1981 (Box 377, Folder 3752)
  - Possible Patrons Dinner with Brzezinski, 1978-1980 (Box 377, Folder 3753)
  - Fundraising Enclosures, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3754)
  - Fundraising, 1981 May-June (Box 377, Folder 3754A)
  - TC Members - Corporation Solicitation Drive, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3755)
  - Master Corporate List for Solicitations (Box 377, Folder 3755A)
  - David Rockefeller Fundraising - Lists of Follow Up Items, 1979-1980 (Box 377, Folder 3756)
  - Corporations Solicited Negative Response, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3737)
  - Enclosures with Corporate Patrons Letters, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3758)
  - Fundraising - Personal and Corporate, 1979 (Box 377, Folder 3759)